

Morgan English

morgan.english.seng@gmail.com
ttps://morgan-english.vercel.app

Professional Summary

Enthusiastic and inquisitive software engineer with a history of success in teaching, applying, and developing technical concepts at a tertiary education level. Experienced in defining and managing large-scale student software projects across agile and waterfall methodologies. Knowledgeable in field of software engineering with experience in web technologies, design and architecture patterns, artificial intelligence, mobile development, continuous integration and deployment, and software security.

Key Soft Skills

- Effective Communication
- Knowledge Sharing
- Dedicated to Learning

- Self-Directed Working
- Analytical Thinking

Key Technical Experience

- Languages: Java, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Kotlin, Python
- Frameworks: React, Vue, Express, Spring, Thymeleaf, JavaFX, Jetpack Compose
- Methodologies: Scrum, Waterfall, Kanban

Experience

Software Engineering Senior Tutor, University of Canterbury, July 2021 - Current, Christchurch

- Supported a wide range of software engineering courses across the 2nd, 3rd, and 4th years.
- Created and continually supported project specifications for team and individual based project courses following both scrum and waterfall methodologies.
- Communicated with and guided student growth in industry-like team software projects.
- Championed the updating of several courses to more recent and widely used technologies.
- Organized and directed several teams of student tutors to ensure courses were taught smoothly.
- Listened to student feedback and continuously incorporated improvements.

Tutor, University of Canterbury, March 2020 - June 2021, Christchurch

- Supported students in development of efficient and effective software development skills.
- Provided private instruction to individuals to improve academic performance and prepare for assessments.

Research Assistant, University of Canterbury, November 2019 - Feb 2020, Christchurch

- Worked under an academic creating a whole slide image viewer GUI application in Python to support research on cancer cell analysis.
- Researched and worked individually consistently meeting with my supervisor to discuss the project and receive guidance.

Software Contractor, Resilient Organisations Ltd, November 2018 - April 2019, Christchurch

- Created a bespoke software solution for customized automated report generation using Java.
- Provided technical support to users and system administrators with documentation and troubleshooting.

VR/Web Intern Developer, Radian Digital, Nov 17 - Feb 18, Nov 18 - Feb 19, Christchurch

- Employed Asp.NET and React frameworks in creating a website.
- Demonstrated VR applications to the public at Ports of Auckland Open Weekend.
- Co-hosted a VR presentation at an IT Professionals NZ meet up.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering with First Class Honours, Software Engineering - April 2020 University of Canterbury - Christchurch

Awards

Engineering Faculty Emerging Teaching Award, Runner-up - November 2024

Personal Interests & Hobbies

Sports/Activities:

- Running, Badminton, Climbing, Weight-Lifting

Hobbies:

- Baking, Software Blogging, Gaming

Links

Website/Blog: https://morgan-english.vercel.app/
GitHub (student): https://github.com/bluewater18
GitHub (professional): https://gitlab.com/morgan-english.seng
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/morgan-english

References

References available upon request.